Guide to the Cornell Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Coalition records, 1967-1999
Cornell Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Coalition records, 1967-1999
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Coalition records, 1967-1999
37-6-1589
Cornell Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Coalition
7.1 cubic feet
Correspondence, logbooks, financial records, accounts, newsletters, bibliographies, minutes, lists, broadsides, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Following Columbia University students’ lead, in May 1968, Cornell student government approved the creation of the second gay college student organization in the nation. Jearld F. Moldenhauer, one of the founders, convinced student government to waive the requirement that the new group submit a list of its members’ names and recruited Father Daniel Berrigan of Cornell United Religious Work to sign on as the first faculty advisor. Founding documents of Cornell’s Student Homophile League (SHL), and correspondence, logbooks, financial records, bibliographies, minutes, photographs, event flyers and broadsides of the SHL and of Cornell student LGBTQIA+ student activism under subsequent names through 1999.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Columbia University's Student Homophile League (SHL), the first college or university student group for gay issues, was founded in October 1966. On March 5, 1968, Jearld F. Moldenhauer, a student at Cornell University, wrote to the business manager of Columbia's SHL, who was using the pseudonym Stephen Donaldson, and stated that he was "seriously considering an attempt to organize a Cornell chapter of the Student Homophile League." Cornell's Scheduling Coordination and Review Board (SCARB) recognized the group in May 1968, and Cornell's Student Homophile League became the country's second gay student organization.
To protect privacy, Moldenhauer arranged for Cornell's SCARB to recognize the group without submitting names of its members. Father Daniel Berrigan of Cornell United Religious Work agreed to sign on as the Cornell group's first faculty advisor. The first widely advertised meeting took place Nov. 21, 1968. Moldenhauer, Janis Kelly, Robert Roth, Janet Hadda, and Pauline Layton were active members and officers during the first few years. Victoria (Vicky) Mead was an officer in the 1978/1979 and 1979/1980 academic years with Alan Evan Cherry, whose 1986 memorial service program is included in the files she donated.
Cornell's SHL brought its first outside speaker to campus, Dr. Franklin Kameny, on Sept. 23, 1969. His lecture, "The Homosexual Dilemma: What Every Heterosexual Should Know," drew an audience of 150. This was followed by an October 23 lecture by Barbara Gittings, "The Lesbian Speaks for Herself," that drew 350 people. In February 1970, through the efforts of then president Robert Roth, Ithaca's leftist print shop, Glad Day Books, printed the first issue of Cornell SHL News. A basement bar named Morrie's started having gay nights and became a social space for SHL members. The Gay People's Center was an affiliated project.
In 1971, a tradition of celebrating May Gay started and has continued since. Sometime after 1984, the celebration was moved to April because of the early ending of the school year and became known as Gaypril.
Name changes:
In September 1970, the SHL changed its name to the Gay Liberation Front. Around 1973, the name changed to Cornell Gay Liberation. Sometime between 1973 and 1979, a group called United Sisters co-sponsored dances with Cornell Gay Liberation. In September 1979, Cornell Gay Liberation became GAYPAC (Gay People at Cornell) and a group named Cornellesbians had formed.
In 1984, the following groups existed at Cornell: GAYPAC, LAGPAD (Lesbian and Gay Political Action Discussion Group); Cornell Women's Center; GBLOC (Gays, Bisexuals, and Lesbians of Color); Gay Peer Counselors; Lambda Law Students; and Cornellesbians.
By 1989, GAYPAC had become the Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual Coalition, an umbrella group including GBLOC and LBQ (Cornell Lesbian, Bisexual, and Questioning Women, formerly Cornellesbians). In 1997, the Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Coalition included: BRIDGES (Bisexuals Reinventing Definitions of Gender and Sexuality); Dialogue (religious discussion group); Safe Space (a coming out support group); ZAP!; LBQ; MSM (Men Supporting Men); and Mosaic (formerly GBLOC).
GUAH (Greeks United Against Homophobia) and Out in the World (the graduate and professional students' LBGT social group) are independent of the Coalition.
The use of pseudonyms:
It will be helpful for researchers to know the pseudonyms used by a few of the early Student Homophile League leaders.
Jearld (Jerry) F. Moldenhauer '68 sometimes used the name Robert Hermann or Robert Herrman, and later, Joel Morrison.
Robert Roth '71 sometimes used the name Robert Russell.
SHL's national chairman was Columbia student Bob Martin, sometimes known as Stephen Donaldson.
CHRONOLOGY
May 4 (5), 1966 or 1967 The founding and subsequent first meeting of the Student Homophile League at Columbia University (Source: The Cornell Daily Sun)
November 10, 1967 Two colleges have joined Columbia & University in establishing budding chapters of the SHL, and additional chapters may be formed by at least some of the other Ivy League universities, according to the groups's national chairman.
Stephen Donaldson (a pseudonym used to maintain the group members' anonymity) said in a telephone interview that prospects are "bright" for the formation of similar homophile groups at other campuses.
A Student Homophile League chapter at Cornell could not be established until a Cornell student contacted Donaldson, the national chair said. No such contact from Cornell has yet been received, he noted.(Source: The Cornell Daily Sun)
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, logbooks, financial records and accounts, newsletters, bibliographies, minutes, lists, and broadsides of and pertaining to gay student groups at Cornell University. Includes twenty volumes of business logs, 1978-1993, of Gay People at Cornell and then the Cornell Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual Coalition.
Photos taken by David Ruether of gay events at Cornell in 1984. They were taken for a story on the student group's 15th anniversary. The story, written by Bill Andriette, ended up not appearing in the alumni magazine.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Coalition.; Cornell Gay Liberation.; Cornell University. Gay Liberation Front.; Gay People at Cornell.; Cornellesbians.; Cornell Lesbian, Bisexual and Questioning Women.; Cornell Gays, Lesbians and Bisexuals of Color.; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University--Societies, etc.; Gay People's Center.; Student Homophile League of Cornell University.; Gay People at Cornell. Advisory Committee on Gay Acquisitions.; Moldenhauer, Jearld.; Kelly, Janis.; Roth, Robert.; Mead, Victoria.
Subjects:
Gay college students.; Gay liberation movement.; Lesbians.; Gays.; Homosexuality.; Bisexuality.; Homosexuals--Societies, etc.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIAL
Daniel and Philip Berrigan collection, #4602.
Robert Roth papers, #7325.
Pauline Layton papers, #7620.
A history of Cornell's Student Homophile League, and transcripts of interviews with SHL founders Jearld Moldenhauer, Janis Kelly, and Robert Roth, can be found in the Haftan M. Eckholdt papers, #7622.
Direct Action to Stop Homophobia (DASH) records, #37-6-3552 (a Cornell LGBT group subsequent to the Coalition).
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
The files had only a rudimentary order. The records of the Gay People's Center are not distinguished from those of the Student Homophile League. The original folder headings, when present, have been retained; others have been supplied. A chronological order has been determined only when practical. Two and a half cubic feet of periodicals have been distributed in other parts of the Human Sexuality Collection.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Records
Boxes 1-5, 9-12
Series II. Photographs
Boxes 6-7, 10
Series III. Ephemera
Boxes 8, 10-11, 13
Series IV. Subject Files
General Subject Files
ACT-UP
AIDS
Conferences
Cornell University Information
Organizations
Series V. Newsletters, Publications, and Other Literature
Box 13
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Records
  - Cornell Gay Liberation Logbook, April 1976-February 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cornell Gay Liberation Logbook, February 1978-August 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Cornell Gay Liberation Logbook, November 1978-March 1979 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Founding of the Student Homophile League at Cornell University, including background material and documents, correspondence from Stephen Donaldson of the National Student Homophile League to Robert Russell, Jerald F. Moldenhauer, and Robert Roth; other correspondence, 1968-70 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Student Homophile League Records and Correspondence, 1969-71 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Student Homophile League Records and Correspondence, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Student Homophile League Records and Correspondence; with reference to the Gay Liberation Front, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cornell Gay Liberation/Gay People's Center's "Gay Liberation Bulletin", 1972-73 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Mrs. Ermanno A. Basilio Correspondence, pertaining to the Ithaca police and other gay issues, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Gay Liberation Front/Gay People's Center Correspondence, 1972-74 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cornell Gay Liberation/Gay People's Center Records and Correspondence, 1975-76 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - Gay People's Center Correspondence, 1975-77 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cornell Gay Liberation Records and Correspondence, 1976-77 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cornell Gay Liberation; "Gay News", 1976-77 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Cornell Gay Liberation Correspondence, 1976-77 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Gay People's Center - Employment, 1976-77 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence and notes, 1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Cornell Gay Liberation/Gay People's Center
    - Records and Correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Minutes, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 18-23)
    - Administrative Records, 1972-1976 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Administrative Records, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Accounts, 1969-1978 (Box 1, Folder 26-41)
    - Zaps: Guidelines and Records, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Posters, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Posters and Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 57-65)
    - Posters and Miscellaneous Printed Material., 1974-1977; Folder 16 includes a 1976 edition of Sex: A Fact Book, given to incoming Cornell students (Box 2, Folder 1-19)
    - Posters, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
  - Nite Court Incident, 1976-77 (Box 1, Folder 42-43)
  - Photograph, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - "The Woman Identified Woman," by Radicalesbians, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Gay Literature and Cornell University Library, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Gay Literature; Bibliographies, 1978-79 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Gay Studies, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Cornell Gay Liberation - Counseling, 1979-80 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence and Clippings re: periodicals, newspapers, radio stations, etc., 1971-76 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Gay Activists Alliance, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Clippings, 1981-83 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Student Homophile Handouts, 1970-71 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Student Homophile League of Columbia University, 1967-69 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Business logs (Box 3)
  - Cornell Gay Liberation Constitution, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1978-80 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1978-1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Printed material, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Printed material, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Publicity, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Gay Studies, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Printed material, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - GAYPAC, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - GAYPAC, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Printed material, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Local resources, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Cornell United Religious Work, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Printed material, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - NYCLU (New York Civil Liberties Union), 1983 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Printed material, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Gay People at Cornell, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Printed material, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - News, 1983-84 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Press releases, 1983-84 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Printed material, c. 1984 (Box 4, Folder 21-24)
  - Gay People at Cornell, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Printed material, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 26-27)
  - Printed material, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 28-30)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - GAYPAC, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Lesbian and Gay Peer Counselors, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Printed material, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 34-35)
  - Cornellesbians
    - Cornellesbians budget, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Cornellesbians, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Cornellesbians, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Cornellesbians, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Coalition, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Printed material, 1986-1989 (Box 4, Folder 41-42)
  - Events, c. 1990 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Printed material, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Psych services (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Printed material, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - ZAPs
    - ZAPs training, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - ZAPs (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - ZAPs, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - ZAPs, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 50-51)
  - Politics, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Speakers, contacts, c. 1984-1989 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Performers, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Bibliographies, 1980-1985 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Book catalogs (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Books bibliography (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Books (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - CUGALA (Cornell University Gay and Lesbian Alumni Association) Book Fund, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Film (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Office equipment (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - GAYPAC - Notes on Gay/Lesbian Literature at Cornell (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Women's newsletters and miscellaneous, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Northeast Lesbian and Gay Student Union Conference (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bisexuality Study Correspondence, Gay Press, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Incoming Mail, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Incoming Mail, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - E-mail, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 7-11)
  - Valentines (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Flyers, 1986, 1991, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Flyers, 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Event flyers, 1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Budget, 1984-1992 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Kate Clinton Performance, 1986-1988 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Dry-transfer lettering (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Electronic mailing list guidelines (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - GAYPAC organizational tree (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Gay and Lesbian Information Project, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Human Relations Training, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - "I Hate Straights", 1990 (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - LABPAD (Lesbian and Gay Political Action and Discussion), 1984 (Box 9, Folder 81)
  - LBQ (Lesbian, Bisexual and Questioning Women) meeting minutes, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - Lesbian, Gay, and Bisexual Resource Office fall programming calendar (Box 9, Folder 83)
  - LGBTRC (Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual and Transgender Resource Center) pamphlet and Spring 1998 newsletter, 1997-1998 (Box 9, Folder 84)
  - Lesbian and Gay Awareness month, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Letters, 1977-1985 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Letters, 1986-1993 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Letters, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Libraries, 1978-1980 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Magazine sales/distribution (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - May Gay Road Rally (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Masculinity workshop (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Meeting minutes - miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Morrie Angell's statement, GLF response, 8-track tape (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - National Coming Out Day/Week, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Office hours (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Organizations: Cornell University, Cornellesbians, 1985-1991 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Organizations: Cornell University, Graduate Lambda Association, 1987-1989 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Organizations: LAGPADG (Lesbian and Gay Political Action and Discussion Group), Cornell University, 1983-1984 (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - Organizations: LGBT Coalition, Cornell University, 1998-1999 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Out of the Darkness, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 78)
  - Peer counseling: intake sheets, 1990-1992 (Box 10, Folder 83)
  - Peer counseling: minutes, info, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - Phone lists (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - Petition of Cornell University Policy on Equal Education and Employment Opportunity, 1978-1984 (Box 10, Folder 87)
  - Petition of Cornell University Policy on Equal Education and Employment Opportunity, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 88)
  - Possible entertainers to invite (Box 10, Folder 92)
  - Possible future events: movies, performers; or acquisitions of books, magazines, films (Box 10, Folder 93)
  - Press releases (some non-CU), 1976-1992 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Press releases, other news and information (some non-CU), 1979-1989 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Records of magazine holdings, 1969-1979 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Resolution to Implement LGB Loving/Learning Unit, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Student LGB organization contact lists (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Survey: Cornell's Lesbian and Gay Political Action Group, documenting discrimination of gay, lesbian and bisexual people at Cornell, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 46-47)
  - Survey: "The experience of gay men and lesbian womyn in the residence halls compared to their 'straight' counterparts (control group)." (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Survey: "effects of our discussion [during LNC In-Service Training on Gay Sexuality, Awareness, Issues and Counseling]" (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - Surveys: miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - Women's Studies Public Events Program, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 55)
  - Women's worksheet (Box 11, Folder 56)
  - Newsletters from Cornell Gay Liberation/GAYPAC: Gay News, GAYPAC News, News from GAYPAC, Till Tomorrow, 1976-1984 (Box 11, Folder 57-58)
  - Business Log (LGB Coalition), Oct. 1990-Nov. 1991 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Coalition Log, Fall 1991-Spring 1992 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Logbook, Fall 1992-Spring 1993 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Log of Requests and Messages (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Lesbian, Gay and Bisexual People of Color Conference, April 11-13, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - From binder labeled "Coalition", 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Series II. Photographs
  - Events and meetings (Box 6)
  - Gay graffiti, campus events, picnics (Box 7)
  - Photographs of Ithacans at National March for Gay Rights, Washington, D.C., 1979 (Box 10, Folder 86)
- Series III. Ephemera
  - 3 T-shirts, 1969-70; a) Two male and two female signs interlinked; silk-screened in Anabel Taylor Hall by people from Cornell who marched in New York City's first Gay Pride March in 1970; the T-shirts were dried on the lawn behind Anabel Taylor and got the attention of the "DU boys" (fraternity). b) NYSCGO (New York State Council of Gay Organizations) shirt was screened in Anabel Taylor for the second New York City Gay Pride March in 1971; Cornell Student Homophile League was involved in an attempt to create a state organization. c) "Buck Anita" shirts, referring to Anita Bryant, were sold by Cornell marchers at the June 1970 New York City Gay Pride March to pay for the cost of transportation to the march. (Box 8)
  - Postcards (Box 10, Folder 94)
  - Posters
    - Posters, 1973-1999, undated (Box 11, Folder 1-18, 20-21)
      - Photo of and posters from Dan Lansner, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 1a)
    - "A Short History of Queer Flyers at Cornell", 1978-1999 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Originals, 1974-1990 (Box 11, Folder 22-23)
    - Posters from other organizations, circa 1976-1997 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Flyers and Event Posters, 1987-1992 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - CD containing Cornell gay dance posters (CD-2026), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Letters
    - Letters to Congress and NY Governor, no date (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Student Essays
    - Term Paper: "Psychology and Homosexuality, or Who Called This a Science, Anyway?", 1981 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Series IV. Subject Files
  - State of New York Division of Alcoholic Beverage Control: Morrie's boycott, 1970-1973 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Merle Woo's Case Against the University of California, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - ACT-UP
    - ACT-UP-Ithaca: agenda, minutes, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - ACT-UP-Ithaca: posters, 1990? (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - ACT-UP-Ithaca: reports, letter re: political action to Ithaca Journal editorials, 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - ACT-UP-New York City, 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - ACT-UP-New York City: clippings, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - ACT-UP-New York City, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - ACT-UP-New York City: clippings, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - AIDS
    - Gannett study, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Groups, 1983-1992 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Local coverage [some national], 1983-1990 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Local education efforts, 1983-1988[?] (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Resources, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Transmission (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - AIDS Awareness Week, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - AIDS Information Table, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Therapies (AIDS), 1990 (Box 11, Folder 52)
  - Adolescent sexuality, 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Albany Legislative Workshop, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Andriette, Bill: Telluride Associate controversy, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Beck, Evelyn Torton, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Bisexual Awareness, 1991-1993 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Body Politic trial, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Buffalo area gay activities (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Catalogs: books, 1978-1997 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Catalogs: courses, School for International Training, 1993-1995 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Catalogs: progressive paraphernalia, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Censorship, 1978-1990 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Chan, June, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Chicago Resource Center, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Civil Liberties Alert, 1983-1985 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - "Clean Up America" advertisement (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Clippings: Local coverage, 1976-1991 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Clippings: National coverage, 1974-1991 (Box 9, Folder 40-41)
  - Clippings and flyers from other organizations and issues, 1978-1982 (Box 9, Folder 87)
  - Clinton, Bill (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Coming Out to Your Parents Guide (PFLAG) (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Common Ground Calendar of Events, 1998? (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Conferences
    - Black Lesbian Conference, New York City, October 8-10, 1982, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - Celebrate the Movement/Planning the Future, Dallas, Texas, August 13-15, 1982, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - International Conference of Gay and Lesbian Jews, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, January 20, 1981, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual People of Color Conference, Cornell University, April 11-13, 1986, 1986
      - Program and publicity (Box 9, Folder 49)
      - Literature, info for program, brochure (Box 9, Folder 50)
      - White Lesbian/Gay/Bisexual Workshops (Box 9, Folder 51)
      - Straight People of Color Workshop (Box 9, Folder 52)
      - Speech transcriptions (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - National Lesbian and Gay Health Conference, San Francisco State University, June 19-22, 1980, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - New York State Lesbian Conference, Binghamton, April 18-20, 1980, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 55)
    - New York State Lesbian Conference, Binghamton, April 10-12, 1981, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 56)
    - Third World Lesbian/Gay Conference, Washington, D.C., October 12-15, 1979, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Constitution for the New York State Gay/Lesbian Youth Caucus, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Cornell University Information